# AJ Bates II

Full Stack Developer

gitHub | Linkedin | Portfolio

aj.bates2.92@gmail.com (612) 743-3196 Minneapolis, Minnesota

# Summary

I am a Full-Stack Web Developer proficient in React, Node, Express, and Postgresql. I have 7 years of experience in customer service and sales, which has allowed me to develop my communication, teamwork, and problem-solving skills. I also have a strong interest in developing technology that genuinely helps people on a daily basis.

#### **Technical Skills**

Language - JavaScript Front-End - jQuery, HTML5, CSS3 Frameworks - React, React Native Back-end - Node.js, Express.js, Postgresql Dev Tools - Git, GitHub, Chrome Dev Tools, Postman

## **Recent Projects**

#### SafeRes | GitHub

- The pandemic brought on a lot of hurdles to overcome in the service industry. One big issue was state-mandated reservations for all restaurants. I saw this as a great opportunity to create a user experience we haven't taken advantage of at the bar we worked at. Not only was this a way to contact people for their reservations, but it also makes it easier for us to contact people if there was an outbreak.
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, React-Spring, Node.js, Express.js, Postgresgl

### tips. | GitHub

- An app designed to help servers and bartenders keep better track of their income. I have worked in the service industry since I was twelve years old. One thing I didn't realize for a long time, is that if you actually know how much money you are making, the easier it is to save money. So I built this app to empower people in the service industry to take control of their income.
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, React-Router, Node.js, Express.js, Postgresql

#### BrewFinder | GitHub

- A relatively simple app that utilizes the google map API to place data from an open-source brewery database. The user searches for a city and the app fetches data from the brewery database. That data is then used to place markers on the map. The user can then click on a marker to get the relevant information.
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery

## Coronavirus Quiz | GitHub

- A simple quiz testing your knowledge on the current pandemic sweeping the planet. I started building this app right at the end of March and added some mild Resident Evil references to add some levity to the crazy time we were going through.
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery

## Experience

**JL Beers**Burnsville, MN

Supervisor/Beertender

December 2015 - Present

- Quickly became an invaluable employee and promoted to supervisor within the first year working there.
- Developed multiple methods that are used to complete a lot of daily tasks, everything from closing the store down quickly and effectively, to spreadsheets used daily to easily split tips up and count down the safe.

Boonya Systems

Bloomington, MN
Account Manager

July 2015 - December 2015

- Rebuilt companies website, still using it today, with a WordPress template that I modified to the best of my ability.
- Built an email marketing campaign targeted at private practices focused on teaching them about HIPAA compliance as it relates to technology.

• Lead multiple speaking engagements with private practice owners and managers teaching them how to better protect their patients sensitive information

### Radiate Digital/LaunchRunner

Savage, MN

Account Executive March 2014 - July 2015

- The first salesperson hired full time at a small web design/marketing company. The company was transitioning to sell custom-designed websites from the ground up at an affordable monthly price. \$99/month for a custom-designed website (no templates).
- Acquired multiple big clients in my first couple of months, as well as multiple monthly based clients.

## Education

THINKFUL

February 2020 - August 2020

Full-Stack Engineering Flex

• JavaScript-based programming boot camp that teaches both front-end and back-end technologies, which enable me to build an app from wireframe and design to building out the database.